<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-02-25T07:32:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Stim: a blog</title><subtitle>an essay a day keeps the therapist away</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Journal Session with Low Vitamin D: In Which the Generally Stoic Narrator Is Harassed by Footnotes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/journal/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Journal Session with Low Vitamin D: In Which the Generally Stoic Narrator Is Harassed by Footnotes" /><published>2025-02-23T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2025-02-23T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/journal</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/journal/"><![CDATA[<p><em>Editor’s Note: The author wanted to include the following instruction to readers: “Make sure they go through the entire piece first, then go back a second time for the footnotes.“ This piece was received via email a little past midnight Cambodia time referring to events that took place on 1/12/2025 in Upstate New York.</em></p>

<p>Daniel LaPointe</p>

<p>Did not take the Vitamin D supplement today or the multivitamin. Though I <em>did</em> go for a two-mile walk outside earlier, this was rather close to sunset. Given that it’s the dead of winter and given that I haven’t eaten any foods containing Vitamin D recently (to my knowledge), I’m likely pretty damn low in the stuff right now. Some observations:</p>

<ul>
  <li>When looking at my phone’s lock screen photo<sup><a href="#fn11" id="fn1">1</a></sup>, I immediately began to think of the depicted mountain range as a 3D object, if that makes sense. That is, I immediately intuited that the image was facing south and that the mountain on the left side of the image depicted the east-most part of the range. My brain (God I hate using that phrase, but it feels appropriate here) then superimposed over the mountains the trail that I followed when hiking them. At various points of interest along the trail – these visible in the image – I involuntarily recalled what the views were like from those points. There was something immensely satisfying about this all playing out so efficiently – in the span of less than a second. Though I’ve long had difficulty locating the right permutation of words to communicate this sensation, the <a href="https://www.stim.blog/random/">Random Walks</a> essay gets at it with: “I just want to… imagine where I am in relation to everything else.”</li>
  <li>To be clear, this doesn’t usually happen. Generally, the lock screen photo is thought of more for what is represents; rather than being a specific mountain range with an information-dense, spatially aware encoding, it is a low-information pointer to the concept of “a mountain range” and to all the cultural connotations that go with that.</li>
  <li>I am reminded of that sentence at the end of Random Walks: “The key is to stop viewing objects as referents to non-sensory thoughts.” Now, at the end of that essay I hinted at a return to the subject and an invocation of the hippocampus. As the state being described right now recalls that described in the first half of <a href="https://www.stim.blog/photos/">How Does One Sort a Box of Old Photos?</a>, and as that latter essay makes explicit reference to the hippocampus, I may finally make good on that promise.</li>
  <li>I felt an immense urge about two hours ago to look over the iPhone Calendar app and scroll all the way from my birth to today. This is a thing I will do from time to time, the idea being to free-associate memories as the months and years roll by. In a really good session of this, things I hardly ever think about are involuntarily recalled and I “learn” something about myself.<sup><a href="#fn22" id="fn2">2</a></sup></li>
  <li>As a general matter, I get the feeling my ability to effectively free-associate these memories has declined over time. Tonight, however, the session went really well. Granted, I didn’t get all the way through my life (and in fact skipped around a bit; I have work tomorrow), I can state that the highly nonverbal “vibes” of the years of my life are alive and well, resting in my brain (<em>shudders</em>, there is it again…) as mountain-range-like, awe-inspiring objects that can be viewed from any one of a very large number of angles.</li>
  <li>So there we have the connection between spatial thinking and the effortless association of personal memories. Given that a part of the brain known as the hippocampus is involved in both of these activities (a fact I picked up in PSY 14 back in the Fall 2020 semester, shout-out to Liz Phelps and Dan Schacter<sup><a href="#fn33" id="fn3">3</a></sup>), I’m inclined to think something about my behavior today diverted blood flow to that region.</li>
  <li>In particular, I felt an immense <em>closeness</em> to the year 2017.<sup><a href="#fn44" id="fn4">4</a></sup> The memories started flooding in: that eight-night run through all the Harry Potter movies with my brother when on winter break after my first semester, that super cool encyclopedia of prehistoric life I got for Christmas<sup><a href="#fn55" id="fn5">5</a></sup>, those nonstop Facebook games with my high school friends<sup><a href="#fn66" id="fn6">6</a></sup>, the explosion onto the scene of r/PrequelMemes, said subreddit not only being actually funny but being so hilarious I genuinely thought I was going to laugh myself to death at one point while browsing it, the heyday of the Harvard Facebook meme page, some less than stellar things about how that semester went I won’t get into here, that time my Mom and brother came out to Boston to visit me for my birthday, etc.</li>
  <li>You know you’ve entered the mindset of a period when a song from that time just instantly starts playing in your head.<sup><a href="#fn77" id="fn7">7</a></sup> Tonight, I found <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J7iCac98TP0">the Pokémon Go Theme</a> internally blasting, followed shortly after by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HSivlaSVk1k">“We Got the Power” by Gorillaz</a>. Among people who think r/place was the coolest thing ever and who say things like “The timeline split <a href="https://www.stim.blog/ode/">after that damn gorilla got shot</a><sup><a href="#fn88" id="fn8">8</a></sup>,” these two songs are very, very zeitgeisty for that period.<sup><a href="#fn99" id="fn9">9</a></sup></li>
  <li>Well, that’s free association for you. This thing is drowning in footnotes. To round this out,<sup><a href="#fn1010" id="fn10">10</a></sup> I’ll mention the last thing I had been doing prior to starting this write-up.</li>
  <li>Quite naturally, I had taken to reading the “Freshman Year Rambles.”<sup><a href="#fn1111" id="fn11">11</a></sup> These are the most interesting and character-revealing things I wrote back then – “free writes” banged out at 3:00 AM in Lamont meant to “warm up my cognitive machinery” but which in reality served as procrastination apparatuses. Ramble #15, which I’ll drop in its entirety, epitomizes the genre. Enjoy the whining.</li>
  <li>Like the author of that piece,<sup><a href="#fn1212" id="fn12">12</a></sup> I’ve got to get some sleep.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="/assets/dan_ramble.pdf">Read this after the footnotes.</a></p>

<hr />

<p>Notes</p>

<!-- this is for first level: 1, 2, 3, 4 -->
<div id="fn11">
  <a href="#fn1">1.</a> 
  <img src="/assets/dan_phone.jpg" alt="Phone image" style="width: 150px; height: auto;" />
    <br /><br />
</div>

<div id="fn22">
  <a href="#fn2">2.</a> Though I do recall having free-associated into existence a memory tonight that made me think “holy crap, I haven’t thought about that in forever,” I cannot, at this moment, recall what that memory was. The little rascal seems to have gotten away, perhaps not to be fished up again for another thirty years.
    <br /><br />
</div>

<div id="fn33">
  <a href="#fn3">3.</a> Did I just…<i>express gratitude?</i> When the hell has that ever happened in one of these?
   <br /><br />
</div>

<div id="fn44">
  <a href="#fn4">4.</a> This closeness isn’t too much of a surprise. A few hours ago, simulating for my own amusement how a run-of-the-mill interaction with my mother’s boyfriend this evening could have played out in a more interesting and highly self-aggrandizing way,<sup><a href="#fnaa" id="fna">a</a></sup> I challenged myself to think of as many things that happened in 2017 as I could while talking to myself in the bathroom mirror.<sup><a href="#fnbb" id="fnb">b</a></sup>
  <br /><br />
</div>

<!-- this is for second level: a, b -->
<div id="fnaa" style="margin-left: 20px;">
  <a href="#fna">a.</a> B is her boyfriend, D is me. This is the simulated conversation. In reality he just looked at the Star Wars photo<sup><a href="#fnii" id="fni">i</a></sup> and thought it was funny.
<br /><br />
D: Yeah, this is one of the things I’m taking out of my room and bringing to the apartment. It comes from November 2010 – the third and greatest of the seven Disney trips.
<br /><br />
B: Hah, you even remember the year!
<br /><br />
D: Yup. If you were to graph the quality of the Disney trips over time you would have – [<i>visually depicts graph, egocentrically failing to account for the fact that B is facing D and that the image needs to be reversed</i>]
<br /><br />
B: Wow, Danny. You’re so smart!
<br /><br />
D: I’m an historian of the self. You say a year and I can immediately begin rattling off things that happened in that year.
<br /><br />
B: Uhhhh, how about 2017?
<br /><br />
D: [<i>UNLOADS</i>]
<br /><br />
</div>

<!-- third level, first set,  is for 4.a.i -->
<div id="fnii" style="margin-left: 40px;">
  <a href="#fni">i.</a> 
  <img src="/assets/dan_star.jpg" style="width: 150px; height: auto;" />
  <br /><br />
</div>

<!-- back to second level, first set,  is for 4.b -->

<div id="fnbb" style="margin-left: 20px;">
  <a href="#fnb">b.</a> And where the hell is this <i>honesty</i> coming from?
  <br /><br />
</div>

<!-- back to first level, 4,5 -->

<div id="fn55">
  <a href="#fn5">5.</a> <a href="https://www.stim.blog/notes/">This sucker</a> is a little lonely. He doesn’t get linked often. Couldn’t help but think of him when the prehistoric life thing came up. He tries his best.<sup><a href="#fnaa2" id="fna2">a</a></sup>
  <br /><br />
</div>

<!-- this is for second set of second level: 5.a -->
<div id="fnaa2" style="margin-left: 20px;">
  <a href="#fna2">a.</a> Am I empathizing with an essay right now?
    <br /><br />
</div>

<!-- back to first level: 6, 7 -->

<div id="fn66">
  <a href="#fn6">6.</a> Endless Lake and EverWing.
  <br /><br />
</div>

<div id="fn77">
  <a href="#fn7">7.</a> I’m reminded of how <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8JZGiY--2LM&amp;t=810s">a variation</a><sup><a href="#fnaa3" id="fna3">a</a></sup> from the last movement of Beethoven’s 30th piano sonata began mysteriously playing in my head when reading <i>The Brothers Karamazov</i>. This was that unspeakably beautiful scene where Alyosha kisses the ground the night of his father’s murder. The reaction I had to this scene, and a comparison of this reaction to how I took in other scenes, is perhaps worth a separate write-up.
  <br /><br />
</div>

<!-- to third set of second level: 7.a -->
<div id="fnaa3" style="margin-left: 20px;">
  <a href="#fna3">a.</a> Stop listening at 14:52.
    <br /><br />
</div>

<!-- back to first level: 8, 9 -->

<div id="fn88">
  <a href="#fn8">8.</a> Damn, we’re bringing everyone to the party.
  <br /><br />
</div>

<div id="fn99">
  <a href="#fn9">9.</a> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=97UR9ixfr0M">Shooting Stars</a><sup><a href="#fnaa4" id="fna4">a</a></sup> is another one.<sup><a href="#fnbb4" id="fnb4">b</a></sup>
  <br /><br />
</div>

<!-- to fourth set of second level: 9.a, 9.b -->

<div id="fnaa4" style="margin-left: 20px;">
  <a href="#fna4">a.</a> I have a fond memory of my freshman roommate finding this particular pairing to be very, very funny. Dude was literally doing the ROFL thing when I showed it to him.
    <br /><br />
</div>

<div id="fnbb4" style="margin-left: 20px;">
  <a href="#fnb4">b.</a> It’s incredible how reliable the nostalgia process is. Plant a seed – even something as ridiculous as skibidi toilet – and it will inevitably bloom.<sup><a href="#fnii2" id="fni2">i</a></sup>
    <br /><br />
</div>

<!-- third level, second set,  is for 9.b.i -->

<div id="fnii2" style="margin-left: 40px;">
  <a href="#fni2">i.</a> Huh. Fellas, is there something <i>old</i> about us?
  <br /><br />
</div>

<!-- back to first level,  is for 10, 11, 12 -->

<div id="fn1010">
  <a href="#fn10">10.</a> Whelp, I’ve made it to 4:00 AM. Though I do work an evening shift, tomorrow is going to be… ugh. I’ll get it on the record that tonight’s behavior is extremely uncharacteristic of how things have gone over the last year or so.
  <br /><br />
  If my general character has changed from what it was in the college days, it’s been a consequence of, well, having to act like an adult.
  <br /><br />
</div>

<div id="fn1111">
  <a href="#fn11">11.</a> One of these was quoted in “Random Walks.”
  <br /><br />
</div>

<div id="fn1212">
  <a href="#fn12">12.</a> 
  <img src="/assets/dan_face.jpg" alt="Phone image" style="width: 150px; height: auto;" />
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Editor’s Note: The author wanted to include the following instruction to readers: “Make sure they go through the entire piece first, then go back a second time for the footnotes.“ This piece was received via email a little past midnight Cambodia time referring to events that took place on 1/12/2025 in Upstate New York.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">After Eating Some Christmas Chocolate</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/chocolate/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="After Eating Some Christmas Chocolate" /><published>2025-01-24T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2025-01-24T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Chocolate</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/chocolate/"><![CDATA[<p>Daniel LaPointe</p>

<p><a href="/assets/dan_choco.pdf">After eating some Christmas chocolate</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Daniel LaPointe]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Document Dump - The Selfish Meme</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/meme/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Document Dump - The Selfish Meme" /><published>2025-01-14T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2025-01-14T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/meme</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/meme/"><![CDATA[<p>Daniel LaPointe</p>

<p>Written 5/25/2022 – so about a month and a half after the bulk of my work on “Learning, Populism, and Reddit” – I was now, all of the sudden, back to liking Reddit. Here, the “last contribution to this blog” referenced is the rather mysterious “<a href="https://www.stim.blog/ode/">Ode to a Sheltered Zoomer</a>”. Like “Ode to a Sheltered Zoomer,” “The Selfish Meme” approaches ironic online culture with a striking sincerity.</p>

<div style="text-align: center; border-bottom: 3px dotted black; line-height: 0.1em; margin: 10px 0 20px;">
</div>

<p>The Selfish Meme</p>

<p><sup><a href="#fn11" id="fn1">1</a></sup> It’s been three months since my last contribution to this blog. Since then, there have been some changes in my life, most notably the death of my grandfather in mid-April. Still being in the thick of it all, I lack the perspective necessary to speak with intelligence about that event. The following words, then, can be thought of as a break from my immediate situation, and as a taste of my present mood.</p>

<p>I currently find myself disillusioned with the humanities. Any statement not backed by data or rigorous argumentation feels utterly worthless to me. No voice is more privileged than any other voice. It is the height of arrogance to hold that the individualized components of one’s writing – one’s cadence, one’s vocabulary, one’s fingerprint–like web of associations – can somehow be superior to those of another person. Whatever ego that had before allowed me to treat my intuition like settled science has now shriveled up. I no longer have the courage to generalize. I no longer have the courage to project my stray thoughts onto others. I am merely one American among some 330 million. I have a “lived experience,” and that is it.</p>

<p>It’s odd that I’ve finally come around to this idea of “lived experience,” given how long I’ve loathed the phrase. After all, there’s no <em>power</em> in speaking from my own, tiny perspective. Make sweeping generalizations, however, and I feel like a tinkerer behind the scenes. Culture is a battleground – and maybe, just maybe, an idea birthed in my head gets broader circulation in the community at large. One can of course pull this off with “data and rigorous argumentation,” but it’s so <em>enticing</em> to think that one’s intuitions can also receive this sort of success.</p>

<p>A few months back I encountered the creator of a superb image – that of the so-called “Lord Marquaad E” – in a Reddit comment section. This user, u/PuppyBaconChips, was responsible for the most iconic variant of the meme, in which a face mash of Markiplier and Lord Farquaad is photoshopped over Mark Zuckerberg’s body.<sup><a href="#fn22" id="fn2">2</a></sup> For those in the know, this image was a watershed moment in meme culture. It marked the culmination of a move toward abstraction that had long been brewing in communities like r/dankmemes and r/deepfriedmemes. What was so astonishing about the image is that no one could explain <em>why</em> it was funny, even though everyone agreed <em>that</em> it was funny. This creation, then, brought us straight into the mind of u/PuppyBaconChips. There was no diffraction by way of shared modes of expression – no erasure of his character by the regularity of things like tropes and explicable visual gags. The meme was funny in a truly elemental way, and for that reason it perfectly reproduced the mental state of its creator.</p>

<p>So, what’s u/PuppyBaconChips up to now? Not much. He’s resting on his laurels, occasionally drawing attention to his creation of the Marquaad image whenever it gets a shoutout.<sup><a href="#fn33" id="fn3">3</a></sup> I’ll note, however, that he tends not to get much notice when he shows up in a comment section. Unlike other social medias, it’s essentially impossible to acquire a following on Reddit. But no matter. If one has truly influenced the surrounding culture, seeing that people have changed their behavior as a result of your actions should be enough. There need not be love-bombing on top of it.</p>

<p>Put another way, u/PuppyBaconChips is content because an idea of his has a <em>robust memetic future</em>. As the theory goes, memes are the units of cultural reproduction. u/PuppyBaconChips can gaze upon his creation much as a parent gazes upon their child. In the same sense that the child guarantees the genetic future of the parent, the success of the u/PuppyBaconChips’ meme guarantees his own memetic future.</p>

<p>Good for him.</p>

<p>Notes:</p>

<div id="fn11">
  <a href="#fn1">1.</a> 
 Title from <i>The Selfish Gene</i> by Richard Dawkins, the book in which the word “meme” was first coined. I have not read this book.
    <br /><br />
</div>

<div id="fn22">
  <a href="#fn2">2.</a> 
  <img src="/assets/dan_zuck.jpg" alt="Phone image" style="width: 150px; height: auto;" />
    <br /><br />
</div>

<div id="fn33">
  <a href="#fn3">3.</a> 
  <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/me_irl/comments/unclxa/me_irl/i88vnwc/?context=3">https://www.reddit.com/r/me_irl/comments/unclxa/me_irl/i88vnwc/?context=3</a> 
    <br /><br />
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Daniel LaPointe]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Document Dump - Learning, Populism, and Reddit</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reddit/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Document Dump - Learning, Populism, and Reddit" /><published>2025-01-06T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2025-01-06T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reddit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reddit/"><![CDATA[<p>Daniel LaPointe</p>

<p>Largely composed piecemeal from January of 2022 to that April, this comes fresh off the heels of <a href="https://www.stim.blog/discourse/">“A Discourse on Atheism”</a> and deals with similar themes. The ultra-granular look at the mechanics of Christian belief bears a passing resemblance to one of Smerdyakov’s arguments from <em>The Brothers Karamazov</em> – the one with Fyodor and Gregory about making a mountain crush Muslim tormenters. The polemics about Reddit, meanwhile, showcase an immense annoyance with a site that had become a major distraction and time sink.</p>

<p>Note that while everything after “And what if this check never occurs in the first place?” was written just now to finish the piece off, the general thrust of the final argument had been worked out in my head at around the time of the original composition.</p>

<div style="text-align: center; border-bottom: 3px dotted black; line-height: 0.1em; margin: 10px 0 20px;">
</div>

<p>To learn is to efface oneself before a master. It is to say, here and now, “I do not know, but I <em>can</em> know.” It is to ready oneself for a complete reshaping of the mind, in which previously inconceivable landscapes are unveiled, peak-in-Darien-like, to the learner’s amazement. Such a posturing requires no shortage of faith in one’s teacher. To lack this faith, in fact, is to abandon learning entirely.</p>

<p>There’s a reason we educate the young and not the old. Those new to the world possess a natural ignorance. They have no choice but to glean information from those around them – hence the steady stream of “Why is the sky blue?” questions which springs forth, perennially, at our nation’s playgrounds. For a good many children, this curiosity stops sometime in elementary school. For the academically inclined, however, it can continue even into adulthood. One’s educational attainment, I posit, owes largely to when one decides to exempt themselves from this mode of existence. When is enough enough? When do you say to yourself, “Alright, I’m up to snuff with the adults. It’s about time we conversed as equals”? If a child’s parents exempted themselves from this process early on – at the age of 10, say – it is only natural that the child will do the same. But what if the child exempts themselves independent of parental approval? What if something in the child’s environment precipitates this?</p>

<p>I argue that no website in the world more effectively catalyzes this exemption process than <a href="https://www.reddit.com/">Reddit.com</a>. Let’s take a look at the facts.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Reddit’s user-base is relatively young – mostly teenagers and young adults. Unlike the known boomer-haven Facebook, Reddit is dominated by people who can still be exempted from the traditional learning process.</li>
  <li>Reddit’s user-base takes pride in its intelligence. As Urban Dictionary puts it, Reddit is “Social media for people who think they are too good for social media.” Visit the site and there is no shortage of complaints about Facebook, Instagram, TikTok, and Twitter. As the Redditors see it, folks who use these apps are vapid and vain (unlike them). Hence the site’s reputation for intellectual arrogance. It is a honey pot, then, for academically inclined teenagers.</li>
  <li>The front page is littered with educational tidbits. Unlike your average piece of TikTok spam – the purpose of which is plainly to divert and amuse – these Reddit posts evince a startling sincerity. The Wikipedia addicts of r/TIL, the non-lawyers of r/LegalAdvice, the randos of r/LifeProTips and r/YouShouldKnow, the armchair psychologists of r/raisedbynarcissists, the quantum-physics-explaining-high-schoolers of r/ELI5 – all of these people genuinely think they are making the world a better place with their subpar advice. And those in the comments tend to eat it right up. The general attitude, it seems, is an unironic “we’re all in this together.” On Reddit, everyone is capable of educating everyone.</li>
  <li>Reddit is virulently anti-religion. While this does not in itself imply the users are incapable of learning (and while I myself have defended atheism on this very blog), it suggests the user-base is extremely hesitant to take leaps of faith. But faith in one’s teacher is essential to proper learning. Indeed, treat your teacher as an equal and you won’t be learning from them so much as you’ll be arguing with them.</li>
  <li>When arguments do break out, Reddit’s culturally enforced anonymity levels the playing field. As a result, we find thirteen-year-olds arguing with day traders arguing with professional historians arguing with depressed coders, etc. This is all fine and dandy, except one hardly ever knows who’s who. And when an expert does out himself, such an admission hardly conveys authority. Having myself browsed the site regularly for over five years, I can say that expertise doesn’t <em>imply</em> authority on Reddit so much as it <em>suggests</em> it. Past success, then, means nothing on Reddit. Posts and comments succeed on merit and on merit alone.</li>
  <li>Reddit has a populist culture more broadly. Recall the anti-Wall-Street sentiment driving the GameStop short squeeze, or the recent ascendency of r/antiwork. This is no surprise, given the egalitarian design of the site itself. When everybody’s a nobody, you might as well identify as a member of a collective.</li>
</ul>

<p>Putting this all together, we find that Reddit has a profound tendency to attract academically promising youth and to undermine the very traits that made them academically promising in the first place. An ability to identify and discount the opinions of intellectual inferiors is replaced with a fetishization of the common man, and with a startlingly predictable acceptance of whatever the hivemind deems correct. An ability to consume long-form content is replaced with the compulsive hoarding of trivialities – a stuffing of the brain with “fun facts” desperately awaiting an opportunity to be loosed at the dinner table. An ability to take things on faith – to let go of one’s ego, temporarily, so as to optimize learning in the long run – is replaced with a myopic insistence that everything be reduced to logos at the drop of a hat.</p>

<div style="text-align: center; border-bottom: 3px dotted black; line-height: 0.1em; margin: 10px 0 20px;">
</div>

<p>I feel a Socratic dialogue coming on. We begin with the Redditor’s rebuttal.</p>

<p>R: I take issue with your claim that Reddit’s atheism is a problem. You yourself have argued for atheism in the past. If we are in agreement on this matter, how am I the inferior one?</p>

<p>D: As stated above, the atheism itself isn’t the problem. It’s the peculiar brand of militant atheism evinced on that page. The sheer unwillingness of the users to consider that maybe, just maybe, there’s merit to these millennia-old traditions.</p>

<p>R: Pick a religion, any religion, and explain to me its merits.</p>

<p>D: That’s getting us off topic. My point is that r/atheism doesn’t have a shred of respect for these institutions, despite their immense cultural and historical significance.</p>

<p>R: The default state with religion is one of non-belief. If you cannot explain to me the merits of religion, I have no reason to take it seriously. The burden of proof is on you.</p>

<p>D: Fine, fine. I wrote an essay about this a few months ago. It’s called “A Discourse on Atheism,” and it can be found elsewhere on this blog. In the essay, I advocate atheism. But I also do my best trying to defend Christianity. I recall being rather convinced by some of the imagined Christian rebuttals.</p>

<p>R: Ok. Provide some of the Christian rebuttals.</p>

<p>D: Here’s one. This isn’t directly from the essay, but the vibe is similar. Suppose you go to work at some office job. It’s early in the morning. You’re groggy and stressed, but your boss walks by and delivers a chipper “Good morning!” How do you respond?</p>

<p>R: I would say “good morning” back to him.</p>

<p>D: As would I. Now suppose he also asks how your day is going, but your day is going terribly. How would you respond then?</p>

<p>R: In the moment, I would lie to him. My response would be something along the lines of “Good, good. How you holding up?”</p>

<p>D: As would I. But why lie to your boss? Shouldn’t one strive to be truthful in one’s interactions?</p>

<p>R: I lie because to tell the truth would be to torpedo the interaction. My boss has neither the time nor the energy for me to open up about something intimate.</p>

<p>D: If that’s the case, why did he ask you the question in the first place? Shouldn’t he have been ready for any response that could have been provided?</p>

<p>R: Not necessarily. The goal of his question wasn’t to elicit information so much as it was to gauge my mood. The speed of the response, my tone of voice, the nature of my eye contact – this is what he really wanted to know.</p>

<p>D: So there exist utterances with meanings that are entirely subtextual?</p>

<p>R: Yes, such utterances do exist.</p>

<p>D: And what if the Bible is nothing but a string of such utterances?</p>

<p>R: Look, if you want to treat the Bible as a work of literature, you can go ahead and do that. I understand metaphors as well as the next guy. But that is not the same thing as being a Christian.</p>

<p>D: How would you define a Christian?</p>

<p>R: A Christian is someone who believes that Jesus Christ died for their sins. They also believe that their holding this belief will result in them going to Heaven when they die.</p>

<p>D: Good. Now suppose someone reads the Bible as they would a work of literature. As you and I would, they dismiss literal interpretations of ridiculous claims. Nevertheless, they walk away from this reading with a conviction to attend Church every Sunday and to partake in Christian rituals. Is such a person not effectively a Christian at that point?</p>

<p>R: Such a person would only be going through the motions. In the absence of genuine belief, they would not be Christian in the truest sense of the word.</p>

<p>D: How would you define “genuine belief” in this case?</p>

<p>R: At the very least this person would have to believe in the resurrection of Christ three days after his crucifixion. This, however, plainly counts as one of the “ridiculous claims” we have assumed to be rejected.</p>

<p>D: Alright. Now suppose this person lies and responds “yes” every time they are asked whether they believe in the resurrection. On what information can we base the claim that they do not <em>truly</em> believe in the resurrection?</p>

<p>R: I’m not sure why you’re asking this. We have assumed at the outset that this person does not truly believe in the resurrection. Hence your usage of the word “lie.”</p>

<p>D: Yes, we did. But suppose we were given a group of random people and asked to sort them into those who truly believe in the resurrection and those who do not. How would we go about sorting those people?</p>

<p>R: If a practicing Christian has never stated that they do not actually believe in the resurrection, we would have no choice but to place them among the believers, regardless of their true stance on the matter.</p>

<p>D: Right. But if that’s the case, how can we be sure that the Christian religion is not full to the brim with people like this? What if the Pope, the bishops, the Protestant pastors – what if they’re all just a bunch of liars who’ve never slipped up?</p>

<p>R: Impossible. Though I disagree with the clergy’s philosophical positions, I do not in any way doubt their sincerity.</p>

<p>D: Suppose you could crack open the minds of these people. Given complete, God-like access to the thoughts of the Pope, say, how could you tell whether his belief in the resurrection is genuine? On a cognitive level, what would you be looking for?</p>

<p>R: Well, we can start with his internal monologue. If he finds himself thinking “I don’t believe what I’m saying” the moment he verbalizes belief in the resurrection, then that would suffice as proof of his non-belief.</p>

<p>D: Just to be crystal clear, you’re referring to the part of the Pope’s brain responsible for producing internalized speech, whatever it may be?</p>

<p>R: Yes, I am.</p>

<p>D: And you’re implying, in this example, that that part of the brain, in that moment, must internally voice the exact sentence “I don’t believe what I’m saying”?</p>

<p>R: Or something equivalent to that, yes. For example: “I’m lying,” “This is false,” “The resurrection never occurred.”</p>

<p>D: What if the Pope just went about his business with no internal monologue whatsoever? Could you imagine a scenario in which we would still be able to pin down nonbelief?</p>

<p>R: In theory, I suppose, the Pope could nonverbally bring to mind the idea that the resurrection did not occur. Though I’m not sure how this would be done on the cognitive level, there’s precedent of mathematicians doing this sort of thing when evaluating the truth or falsehood of propositions. That is, they make use of a visuo-spatial intuition that exists independent of language.</p>

<p>D: But would this on its own imply that the Pope does not believe in the resurrection? It is possible to bring an idea to mind – internally voiced or not – without endorsing it. Indeed, one can imagine the Pope viewing the idea “from a distance.” That is, he could recognize the idea, classify it as an impulsive thought, and separate it from the self.</p>

<p>R: Correct. And in that moment, he would be replacing the thought with an updated thought. Since the new thought clarifies that the resurrection did, in fact, occur, it would follow that the Pope is not lying.</p>

<p>D: But what about that brief moment in time when he entertained the thought that the resurrection never occurred? Are we to take that thought as representative of the Pope’s true self?</p>

<p>R: No, we are not. If the Pope recognizes this thought as impulsive and chooses to replace it with another thought, then we would say that it is not representative of his true self.</p>

<p>D: But recall that we are thinking about this on the cognitive level. If the Pope replaces the internally voiced sentence “The resurrection did not occur” with the internally voiced sentence the “The resurrection did occur,” is there anything we’d be able to detect in the brain that would distinguish these two thoughts?</p>

<p>R: Though I am no expert on such matters, I believe the latter statement would be made following increased activity in the pre-frontal cortex.</p>

<p>D: So a thought which is brought to mind is only taken to be representative of one’s true self if it survives a check from the rational part of the brain?</p>

<p>R: That is correct.</p>

<p>D: And what if this check never occurs in the first place?</p>

<p>R: What?</p>

<p>D: What if the Pope voices belief in the resurrection through sheer force of habit? What if there’s <em>nothing</em> going through his mind when he does this?</p>

<p>R: Well now we’re back to where we were before. He’s going through the motions and it’s hard to say what he actually believes.</p>

<p>D: And what’s wrong with that?</p>

<p>R: Huh?</p>

<p>D: If he’s partaking in all the Christian rituals with no contradictory thoughts in his head, then we would say that he’s a perfectly operating Christian at that point, would we not?</p>

<p>R: But he’s not independently affirming the belief.</p>

<p>D: And this is my problem with the Reddit mindset. At some point you just have to <em>shut up and put yourself out there</em>, you know? Arbitrarily stake a claim because it’s what your upbringing handed you; take up a spot in the world as a flesh-and-blood human being situated in a network of other flesh-and-blood human beings and do what your social intuition tells you is necessary.</p>

<p>R: Alright, so you’ve given up on being rational at this point.</p>

<p>D: No I haven’t. I’ve just laid down an extra axiom.</p>

<p>R: You can’t do that.</p>

<p>D: Why not?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Daniel LaPointe]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Taken from His Own Words</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/words/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Taken from His Own Words" /><published>2024-12-26T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2024-12-26T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Father-Joe</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/words/"><![CDATA[<p>James Song</p>

<p>Thursday, Sept 12, 2024.</p>

<p>Father Cho, a Jesuit priest, was new to the school I’m volunteering at, though not new to Cambodia—he’s been here longer than I’ve been alive. He is one of a dozen or so Jesuit priests in Cambodia. He was sent from Phnom Penh, the capital, to be one of the directors of the school here in the rural area.</p>

<p>He and I sat down one night after a dinner with the secondary school teachers. There were sixteen of them. He had met them for the first time and remembered all their names. We talked for about two hours—or at least he did, and I listened—over the last of my cigarette, about two puffs, and four of his, though he smoked only till half way or so, popping the blue mint capsules and tapping them on the box before lighting them. His words<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> are <em>italicized</em>, edited for coherence.</p>

<p style="text-align: center;">*</p>

<p>The story of how Father Cho met Jesus.</p>

<p><em>Three things happened when I was in ninth grade.</em></p>

<p><em>There was a book at home that stood out to me. The title and the author I cannot forget. At that age, I thought science was the truth—we were learning about evolution and so on in school. But I read that book and the guy was talking about how science fits in with religion. I was young and didn’t get much of it, but I had some knowledge of this stuff in my head.</em></p>

<p><em>Then there was my second older brother, who was studying at Seoul National University at the time. This guy was much older and smarter than me. I respected him. He was taking Catholicism seriously and kept talking about Jesus with my mom. That got my attention.</em></p>

<p><em>And then there was a Catholic retreat I went to. In those days, boys’ schools were separate from girls’ schools, and I was curious about girls. The retreat was a day long. There was a guy named Paul, who was so nice to me. He was introducing me to all the girls, and I was excited. Then, at night, we were standing in a circle for group prayer. The leader—he was a young lay Catholic guy—got us together and said that there was one member who was sick and that we should pray for him together. That member had a bad leg that made him limp. His name was Paul.</em></p>

<p><em>At this point I prayed a prayer. I prayed many times before during Mass—I used to follow my mom there—but it was the first time in my life that I truly prayed. I prayed that Paul’s pain would be given to me instead—the selfish me that was so into meeting girls that I didn’t even notice Paul’s bad leg.</em></p>

<p><em>Then, like Elijah and the priests of Baal in the Bible<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup>, the Holy Spirit came down like a pillar of fire. I felt my body burning. I was shaking to the core—even now I tremble when I talk about it. I had a cool head—I could think clearly—but my whole body was hot. And I saw Jesus on the cross, bleeding. He was talking to me: “Do you see why I died? I died for your sins.”</em></p>

<p><em>Then I saw my life like a panorama, with all the moments where I sinned. I was in ninth-grade—what sin could a boy have? And I prayed two things—and this is true prayer: one, that Jesus would forgive me, that I was sorry; and two, for others, that my friend would be healed and that his sickness would come upon me in his place. He listened to the first prayer, but not the second.</em></p>

<p><em>In my mind, this went on for five minutes. When I came to myself again, the prayer circle was gone, and three or four hours had passed. From that day on, I went to Mass out of my own volition.</em></p>

<p><em>After that, like I was telling you yesterday, I proclaimed the Gospel to everyone with the passion of a Protestant—just naturally—with the fire that was in me. My friends would ask me questions about God, and the words that came out of my mouth in reply made them cry. And we went to Mass together.  A third of my ninth-grade classmates became Catholic. One is now a parish priest in Gangnam. He always jokes that I’m the reason he’s stuck as a priest. To this day he supports the Cambodia Mission.</em></p>

<p><em>But I also realized, through studying philosophy and theology at higher levels, that feeling is not everything. It’s much bigger than that. Passion alone means little.</em></p>

<p style="text-align: center;">*</p>

<p>On Mother Theresa and the dark night of the soul, when she felt abandoned by God for the last fifty years of her life.</p>

<p><em>It is a gift from God that she was allowed to struggle with her faith. The closer we get to God, the more unbearable it will be. Look at Moses.<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup> We will burn and die if we see God.</em></p>

<p style="text-align: center;">*</p>

<p>Ants and God.</p>

<p><em>Look at ants. They live in two dimensions. In order to tell ants about the human world, a human will have to become an ant and tell them about the three-dimensional human world. And do you think ants will understand? Of course not. But their world is part of the human world. God is in the fourth, fifth, sixth—the eternal dimension. We cannot understand everything.</em></p>

<p style="text-align: center;">*</p>

<p>Christianity in Europe and Asia.</p>

<p><em>After five hundred years of Christian Europe pouring their wealth and effort on Asia, Christians in Asia made up less than three percent of the total population. We have to think deeply about why that was.</em></p>

<p><em>In Europe, what people care about is Truth. Even if institutions are corrupt, people will accept the Truth. In Asia, this is not the case. Jesus said he is the Way, the Truth, and the Life. In Europe, what compels people is Truth. In Asia, what matters is the Way. That explains the popularity of Buddhism—there is the clear eightfold-path. Muslims have clear practices—fasting in Ramadan, the five prayers a day, and so on. In Chinese philosophy, there is Confucianism and Daoism–clear directions on how to live. Christians—all we do is fight each other. We haven’t been able to show the Way.</em></p>

<p><em>There are these two sayings in Korean: 언행일치 and 언행불일치. The first one means that what you say and what you do are consistent. The second is a way of making fun of hypocrites—those that say something and do something else.</em></p>

<p><em>People around you are watching. You don’t have to say anything. They know what you believe. All we have to do is embody the spirit of Jesus.</em></p>

<p><em>But we cannot fully be like Jesus, and we have to admit this. Some are called to be martyrs. We have Jesuits in India and elsewhere being persecuted and dying for the faith. I lived in villages with Khmer people for three years when I was studying Khmer. I could do that sort of thing until my mid-thirties, but then my body wouldn’t let me continue. If I continued to eat and live the way my Khmer village friends did, maybe I would have died. Now, here in the community house, even wanting to install AC in my room—I am humble enough to admit this. All these good facilities—this is for the purpose of service. But each person is different and must discern what they are called to do.</em></p>

<p style="text-align: center;">*</p>

<p>On Korean Protestants.</p>

<p><em>Conservative Korean Protestants are not aware of how fundamentalist and marginal they are. The Americans that brought Protestantism to Korea were fundamentalist. The danger in inter-religious dialogue is when people start to say, “I am right and you are wrong.” Fundamentalists are sure they know everything. This is very dangerous.</em></p>

<p style="text-align: center;">*</p>

<p>On his life.</p>

<p><em>I was not supposed to be born.</em></p>

<p><em>I was very poor, so poor that one of my older sisters died as a child from malnutrition. People called my mom crazy for being pregnant with me, and even my dad was telling her to get rid of me. But Catholics believe that life is granted by God. So she kept me.</em></p>

<p><em>We were so poor we were evicted from our house when I was young. I figured the thing that caused my mom the most pain was poverty. All I wanted to do was make money for my mom. I can take care of her by making a lot of money.</em></p>

<p><em>But my mom would always whisper in my ear that I would become a priest. She had given my life up to God. I would follow her to Mass, but I didn’t really care. I even took my tithe and bought comic books! I was taught at church about hell, so in the back of my mind the idea of hell was scaring me while I read the comic books—haha! I was always uncomfortable, but that was all theory—which shows the uselessness of theory. Because the enjoyment I got from the comic books was greater than the intellectual threat of hell.</em></p>

<p style="text-align: center;">*</p>

<p>On faith.</p>

<p><em>What is faith? Faith is belief in the miracle of loving service. It is a miracle that God provides people with love in their hearts to serve to bring about his kingdom. So I’m very thankful for you and for donors who make this school possible.</em></p>

<p style="text-align: center;">*</p>

<p>On the Cambodia Mission.</p>

<p><em>The Jesuits needed someone who truly understood Buddhism. So I was given the mission of studying Buddhism in Sri Lanka and became an ordained Buddhist monk. Actually, most of my friends in Cambodia are monks.</em></p>

<p><em>For me, there were two motivations. There was intellectual curiosity, but that was secondary. Mainly, it was love. How can you show Cambodians that you love them? You must know them. So in Cambodia, you</em> must <em>understand Buddhism.</em></p>

<p><em>For me, two things are important about Cambodia. The raising of influential people in all areas of society who are competent—have the head—but not just that: nurturing people who also have conscience—the right heart. Second, it is good Buddhism. I have a Ph.D., but a monk’s words are a hundred times more influential in Cambodian society. If Cambodian Buddhism is solid, Cambodian society will thrive.</em></p>

<p><em>As for the Catholics, after twenty-five years of supporting 130 schools—we’ve supported Cambodia by paying salaries, training teachers, building schools—we realized that we needed to build our own school and operate it ourselves. That’s why this school was built.</em></p>

<p><em>Right now we’re stretched too thin. If I were here, I would have advocated for having only the middle and high schools. Then maybe our impact would have been greater. I would have voiced this more strongly, but I was abroad studying…</em></p>

<p><em>Nurturing leaders means teaching them English, which is why your mission is so important.</em></p>

<p><em>God plants seeds among the poor.</em></p>

<p style="text-align: center;">*</p>

<p>On Jesus.</p>

<p><em>The question is, whatever it is we do, can we do it not out of our own enjoyment of our talent or to create a persona or a public image or for anything else like that, but in service of love for others? Jesus summed up all the laws and the prophets with two commandments<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup>—love God and love others. Before he died, as a kind of will—wills are very important, we listen to the wills of dying people—he condensed the two commandments into one: as I have loved you, love others.<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">5</a></sup></em></p>

<p><em>The foundation of our faith is the love of Jesus for us. Our foundation is not dogma or creed or proclamation.</em></p>

<p><em>Ask Jesus to show you his love. He gives when you ask sincerely.</em></p>

<p style="text-align: center;">*</p>

<p>His goodbye.</p>

<p><em>Today, I ended up ranting for a while. Good night.</em></p>

<p style="text-align: center;">*</p>

<p>There was more that he said: an account of the moral leadership of Catholic priests during the democratic protests in the 80s in Korea; his evaluation of Protestant missionaries’ work in Cambodia; references to the Bible, including extended quotes of Matthew 25 (all five pieces of detail) in talking about Judgement Day; analyses of the Gospels, in particular of Matthew 13 and 15; explanations of various symbols, like Jesus’ washing of his disciples’ feet and the symbolism behind the miracle of the five loaves and two fish; the title and author of the book he read in ninth grade; anecdotes that showed ways that God reveals himself to us. But the essential details of the conversation are above.</p>

<p>-</p>

<p>Notes:</p>

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>There is no one-to-one map that can translate the full meaning of Korean sentences to English sentences, and each sentence is embedded in a web of cultural understanding which it would take living in that culture for a long time for you to fully get. And there is his alpha personality, his swagger, his poise, and, in recounting the most precious moment, his encounter with Jesus, his very soft voice.  And his humor is not really captured. We laughed a lot, he more than I. All of it was said in the tone of a cool and caring senior, like that of an affectionate, experienced older brother giving relationship advice. Normally, Koreans don’t use this comfortable way of speaking until they are close with you. It may rub people the wrong way. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
      <p><a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=1%20Kings%2018%3A22-39&amp;version=NIV">1 Kings 18:22-39</a>. <a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3">
      <p><a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Exodus%2033%3A18-20&amp;version=EXB">Exodus 33:18-20</a> <a href="#fnref:3" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:4">
      <p><a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Matthew%2022%3A37-40&amp;version=NIV">Matthew 22:37-40</a> <a href="#fnref:4" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:5">
      <p><a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=John%2013%3A34&amp;version=NIV">John 13:34</a> <a href="#fnref:5" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[James Song]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Document Dump – Pharmapolitics and the Vitamin D Hypothesis</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hypothesis/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Document Dump – Pharmapolitics and the Vitamin D Hypothesis" /><published>2024-12-24T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2024-12-24T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Hypothesis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hypothesis/"><![CDATA[<p>Daniel LaPointe</p>

<p>Unlike those two “Intimations” submissions from earlier in the year <a href="https://www.stim.blog/intimations/">here</a> and <a href="https://www.stim.blog/authenticity/">here</a>, this one actually builds to a concrete, falsifiable hypothesis. Left unsaid is the context of my job. As a call center agent working for a welfare program, I found that my implicit judgment of callers would vary with whether I had taken a Vitamin D supplement in the morning.</p>

<p>Note that the following scan is of a verbatim re-write of what I had initially penned on 7/16/2023; the original is littered with scribbles and is close to illegible.</p>

<p><a href="/assets/dan_hypothesis.pdf">Pharmapolitics and the Vitamin D Hypothesis</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Daniel LaPointe]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Interruption to the Document Dump - Some Thoughts on Luigi</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/interruption/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Interruption to the Document Dump - Some Thoughts on Luigi" /><published>2024-12-11T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2024-12-11T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Interruption</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/interruption/"><![CDATA[<p>Daniel LaPointe</p>

<p><a href="/assets/dan_inter.pdf">A bout of journaling that just kept going.</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Daniel LaPointe]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Document Dump - How Does One Sort a Box of Old Photos?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/photos/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Document Dump - How Does One Sort a Box of Old Photos?" /><published>2024-12-03T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2024-12-03T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Photos</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/photos/"><![CDATA[<p>Daniel LaPointe</p>

<p>Coinage of “meanerwhile,” a clutch <em>Little Prince</em> quote, an absolute banger of an 85-word sentence – it’s hard to say why I sat on this one for so long. The primary holdup, as far as I can tell, was my concern that listing the names of the four books described in the second bullet point would cause a new line to form and make the aesthetically pleasing paragraph at the bottom of the page bleed onto the next page. Apparently, it took me over a year (the piece being originally written in September of 2023) to settle on “three field guides and a book about eastern alpine hiking.”</p>

<p>And let’s be real. The look of the paragraphs is absolutely relevant to one’s experience of a piece of writing. For more on this, see <a href="https://www.stim.blog/random/">the following</a>.</p>

<p><a href="/assets/dan_photos.pdf">So yeah, this one’s a PDF.</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Daniel LaPointe]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Document Dump - Presidents Godfather Tier List Part II</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tierii/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Document Dump - Presidents Godfather Tier List Part II" /><published>2024-11-27T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2024-11-27T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Doc-Godfather-two</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tierii/"><![CDATA[<p>Daniel LaPointe</p>

<p>It’s last week. Your humble narrator has just recovered a treasure trove of documents from his crashed laptop. Looking to round out <a href="https://www.stim.blog/tier/">a story he had begun a year and a half ago</a>, he takes the day off from work and follows the characters wherever they lead…</p>

<p><a href="/assets/dan_tierii.pdf">Presidents Godfather Tier List Part II</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Daniel LaPointe]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Document Dump - Introduction</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/introduction/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Document Dump - Introduction" /><published>2024-11-25T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2024-11-25T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Doc-Introduction</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/introduction/"><![CDATA[<p>Daniel LaPointe</p>

<p>With the exception of “Presidents Godfather Tier List – Part II” and the tail-end of “Learning, Populism, and Reddit,” the following six submissions of mine were written quite some time ago and were recently recovered from a laptop that had crashed. Special thanks to Zach from Eyemax Computer Geeks for helping me get the documents back. That $200 went a long way.</p>

<p>Time appears to have thawed out whatever perfectionistic impulses had kept these documents hidden. While they are by no means everything I’ve been sitting on, I’d consider them to be the most complete. Enjoy, fellas.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.stim.blog/tier/">Document Dump - Presidents Godfather Tier List</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.stim.blog/tierii/">Document Dump - Presidents Godfather Tier List Part II</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.stim.blog/photos/">Document Dump - How Does One Sort a Box of Old Photos?</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.stim.blog/hypothesis/">Document Dump - Pharmapolitics and the Vitamin D Hypothesis</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.stim.blog/reddit/">Document Dump - Learning, Populism, and Reddit</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.stim.blog/meme/">Document Dump - The Selfish Meme</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Daniel LaPointe]]></summary></entry></feed>